[
    {
        "question": "Which institution has the Supreme Court appointed to prepare a plan for improving Delhi's green cover?",
        "options": [
            "Forest Research Institute (FRI)",
            "Indian Institute of Forest Management",
            "National Environmental Engineering Research Institute",
            "Central Pollution Control Board",
            "NGT"
        ],
        "answer": "Forest Research Institute (FRI)"
    },
    {
        "question": "At which port did India's Matsya-6000 submersible successfully complete its wet tests, moving closer to the 500m shallow-water trials by 2025 as part of the Samudrayan Project under the Deep Ocean Mission?",
        "options": [
            "Chennai Port",
            "Visakhapatnam Port",
            "Mumbai Port",
            "Kattupalli Port",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the theme of the first-ever Regional Dialogue on the Global Coalition for Social Justice, scheduled for February 24-25, 2025, in New Delhi?",
        "options": [
            "\"Sustainable Development through Green Business\"",
            "\"Innovation for Social Justice and Equality\"",
            "\"Empowering Communities for Global Progress\"",
            "\"Responsible Businesses for Inclusive & Sustainable Societies\"",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "\"Responsible Businesses for Inclusive & Sustainable Societies\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was India's first vertical bifacial solar plant inaugurated by the Union Minister for Housing and Urban Affairs and Power Manohar Lal?",
        "options": [
            "Chennai",
            "Mumbai",
            "New Delhi",
            "Bengaluru",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which scheme has been extended to 2025-26 with the provision of 100% pulse procurement for the next four years?",
        "options": [
            "PM-KISAN",
            "PM-AASHA",
            "Fasal Bima Yojana",
            "National Food Security Scheme",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "PM-AASHA"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ministry is organizing the Aadi Mahotsav 2025, from February 16 to 24, 2025, at Major Dhyan Chand National Stadium, New Delhi?",
        "options": [
            "Ministry of Tribal Affairs",
            "Ministry of Culture",
            "Ministry of Social Justice and Empowerment",
            "Ministry of Rural Development",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Ministry of Tribal Affairs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organizations launched the 'AI for Entrepreneurship' initiative to train 1 lakh youth?",
        "options": [
            "MSDE, NSDC, and Intel India",
            "AICTE, Ministry of Education, and Google",
            "NITI Aayog, ISRO, and Intel India",
            "Ministry of Electronics and IT, IBM, and NSDC",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "MSDE, NSDC, and Intel India"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum health insurance coverage provided under the Ayushman Bharat Vay Vandana Scheme for senior citizens?",
        "options": [
            "₹5 lakh per year",
            "₹10 lakh per year",
            "₹2 lakh per year",
            "₹3 lakh per year",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organization launched the J. C. Bose Grant (JBG) to support senior Indian scientists and engineers in advancing research?",
        "options": [
            "Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR)",
            "Anusandhan National Research Foundation (ANRF)",
            "Department of Science and Technology (DST)",
            "Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO)",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Anusandhan National Research Foundation (ANRF)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the full form of the NAKSHA program that aims to create and update land records in urban areas?",
        "options": [
            "National Agricultural Knowledge-based Survey of Habitations",
            "National Automated Knowledge Survey for Housing Applications",
            "National Aerial Knowledge-based Survey for Housing Authorities",
            "National Geospatial Knowledge-based Land Survey of Urban Habitations",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "National Geospatial Knowledge-based Land Survey of Urban Habitations"
    },
    {
        "question": "Union Government released XV Finance Commission Grants for Rural Local Bodies (RLBs) of Bihar, Haryana, and Sikkim for FY 2024-25. Find how many of them are rightly matched?\n1. Bihar - ₹869.74 crore\n2. Haryana - ₹210.07 crore\n3. Sikkim - ₹6.26 crore",
        "options": [
            "Only 1 and 2 are correct",
            "Only 2 and 3 are correct",
            "All are correct",
            "Only 1 and 3 are correct",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "All are correct"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which power station won the 1st prize for official language implementation at the Regional Official Language Conference in Jaipur?",
        "options": [
            "Bhakra Nangal Power Station",
            "Salal Power Station",
            "Tehri Power Station",
            "Sardar Sarovar Power Station",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Salal Power Station"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Open Network for Digital Commerce (ONDC) initiative was incorporated as a non-profit, Section-8 company and incubated at the ______.",
        "options": [
            "NITI Aayog",
            "Quality Council of India",
            "Reserve Bank of India",
            "Ministry of Commerce and Industry",
            "National Informatics Centre"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the key objective of the Aircraft Leasing Bill approved by the Indian government in 2024?",
        "options": [
            "To introduce new airlines in India, thereby making the airline market more competitive",
            "To build new aircraft manufacturing facilities in India via international collaboration",
            "To increase regressive tax benefits for airline operators.",
            "To reduce airfares by lowering leasing and financing costs for airlines.",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "To reduce airfares by lowering leasing and financing costs for airlines."
    },
    {
        "question": "Who will be the Chief Guest at India's 76th Republic Day celebrations in 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Australian Prime Minister",
            "Indonesian President",
            "Canadian Prime Minister",
            "UK Prime Minister",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "The newly inaugurated Sonamarg Tunnel by PM Modi ensures all-weather road connectivity between which two locations in Jammu and Kashmir?",
        "options": [
            "Gagangeer and Sonamarg",
            "Srinagar and Leh",
            "Sonamarg and Kargil",
            "Jammu and Sonamarg",
            "Srinagar and Sonamarg"
        ],
        "answer": "Gagangeer and Sonamarg"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who launched Phase 4 of the National Educational Alliance for Technology (NEAT 4.0) in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Ministry of Education",
            "University Grants Commission (UGC)",
            "All India Council for Technical Education (AICTE)",
            "National Board of Accreditation (NBA)",
            "National Testing Agency (NTA)"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "At which forum did Piyush Goyal launch the 'Bharat Cleantech Manufacturing Platform,' aimed at boosting solar, wind, hydrogen, and battery sectors, and positioning India as a global leader in clean energy manufacturing?",
        "options": [
            "Bharat Sustainability Summit",
            "Bharat Climate Forum 2025",
            "India Renewable Energy Forum",
            "Global Green Energy Summit",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which report stated that India's poverty rate fell below 5% in 2024, with rural poverty at 4.86% and urban poverty at 4.09%?",
        "options": [
            "RBI Report",
            "NITI Aayog Report",
            "SBI Report",
            "Ministry of Finance Report",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "SBI Report"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which scheme has the Rural Development Ministry approved 56 watershed development projects worth ₹700 crore, covering approximately 2.8 lakh hectares across 10 states?",
        "options": [
            "MGNREGA",
            "National Water Mission",
            "Soil Health Management Scheme",
            "PMKSY-WDC 2.0",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the foundation stone for the new Central Ayurveda Research Institute building laid by PM Modi?",
        "options": [
            "Bengaluru",
            "Mumbai",
            "New Delhi",
            "Hyderabad",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "New Delhi"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the closing event of the \"Hamara Samvidhan Hamara Swabhiman\" campaign organized?",
        "options": [
            "Haridwar",
            "Nashik",
            "Prayagraj",
            "Rishikesh",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "In September 2024, India surpassed which milestone in renewable energy capacity?",
        "options": [
            "100 GW",
            "150 GW",
            "200 GW",
            "250 GW",
            "300 GW"
        ],
        "answer": "200 GW"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which app was launched by Union Minister Jyotiraditya Scindia to enhance telecom security and accessibility for citizens?",
        "options": [
            "National Broadband App 2.0",
            "Sanchar Saathi Mobile App",
            "Intra Circle Roaming App",
            "DBN-Connectivity App",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Sanchar Saathi Mobile App"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the Indian Army's Motorcycle Rider Display Team that set a new world record with a 20.4-foot-high human pyramid comprising 40 men on 7 motorcycles, traveling 2 kilometers along Kartavya Path?",
        "options": [
            "Bravehearts",
            "Avengers",
            "Daredevils",
            "Thunderbolts",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Daredevils"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which edition of National Voters' Day was observed on January 25?",
        "options": [
            "15th",
            "16th",
            "18th",
            "20th",
            "21st"
        ],
        "answer": "15th"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the newly launched platform for managing business and organizational documents?",
        "options": [
            "DigiLocker Pro",
            "Entity Locker",
            "BizLocker",
            "Bharatiya Tijori",
            "IndiaSafe"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    }
]